<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Swift on Rod Schmidt</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/swift/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Swift on Rod Schmidt</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 10:41:54 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/swift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pointfree&#39;s SyncUps App: A Great Example Architecture for a SwiftUI App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/syncups/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 10:41:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/syncups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In comments to my last article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/composable-architecture-experience&#34;&gt;The Composable Architecture&lt;/a&gt; readers have asked about examples of how I think an app should be written. In the article, I did mention my previous posts, which have examples for Clean Swift and MVVM, but those were written for UIKit. SwiftUI didn’t exist at the time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, this article will talk about what I think is a great example of architecture for a SwiftUI app. Pointfree’s own &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pointfreeco/syncups&#34;&gt;SyncUps&lt;/a&gt; app. The example actually has 2 apps, one showing tree-based navigation, and one showing stack-based navigation. For this article, I will just focus on the stack-based example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Composable Architecture: My 3 Year Experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/composable-architecture-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 11:35:37 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/composable-architecture-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently finished a 3 year stint with a company that uses the Composable Architecture (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pointfreeco/swift-composable-architecture&#34;&gt;TCA&lt;/a&gt;)&#xA;from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pointfree.co&#34;&gt;PointFree&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to write about my experiences with TCA and some of&#xA;the problems I see with it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think Brandon Williams and Stephen Cellis, the creators of TCA, are absolutely brilliant, and what&#xA;they have managed to pull off with the creation of TCA is amazing. However, It’s just the two of them,&#xA;and nobody, or no thing, is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift UI &amp; App Architecture: A New Approach Required</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/swift-ui-app-architecture-a-new-approach-required/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 17:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/swift-ui-app-architecture-a-new-approach-required/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With SwiftUI, everything has changed. As Brent Simmons said, it’s the end of the NeXT era and the beginning of the Swift era.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the coming of SwiftUI, most of our app architectures are no longer valid (or at least parts of them). They need to be adjusted. MVC is certainly out. In fact, even controllers seem to be out. From Apple’s content, it seems all we have is models and views, and that’s true. Bindings have seemingly replaced controllers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Clean Architecture: An Example</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-clean-architecture-an-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 21:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-clean-architecture-an-example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I’d like to take an example iOS app written with an MVC architecture and show you what the example would be with a Clean Swift architecture. The example I’ve chosen to use is the Quiz app from chapter 1 of the 3rd edition of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/iOS-Programming-Ranch-Guide-Guides/dp/0321821521/ref=sr_1_7?crid=393OBE770KCSR&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=big+nerd+ranch+ios+programming&amp;amp;qid=1586836438&amp;amp;sprefix=Big+nerd+ranch%2Caps%2C182&amp;amp;sr=8-7&#34;&gt;iOS Programming: The Big Nerd Ranch Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Quiz is a simple app that is like flash cards. It looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img style=&#34;display: block; margin: 0.7rem auto; border: 1px solid black; margin-bottom: 0px;&#34; &#xA;       src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/quiz.png&#34; &#xA;       title=&#34;&#34; &#xA;       alt=&#34;&#34;&#xA;       &#xA;  &gt;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center; font-size: smaller;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways to Avoid Force Unwrapping</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/5-ways-to-avoid-force-unwrapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 18:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/5-ways-to-avoid-force-unwrapping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone on the reddit iOS Programming group asked &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/iOSProgramming/comments/5bm9j7/what_are_the_mistakes_generally_done_by_ios/&#34;&gt;“What are the mistakes generally done by iOS developers while coding in Swift?”&lt;/a&gt;A lot of comments were about using force unwrapping on optionals. Comments such as:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Force unwrapping everything&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Using pyramids of if-let as opposed to guard statements&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;var firstName: String!&lt;/code&gt; ugh&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Overuse of force unwrapped optionals. I cringe when I see that especially when a simple one-liner guard statement would make the code a ton safer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, I thought I would address these concerns and list 5 ways you can avoid force unwrapping.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 4: What Are the Downsides to Putting the Core Data MOC in the App Delegate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/part-4-what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 21:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/part-4-what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/part-3-what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/&#34;&gt;part 3&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about why putting the MOC in the app delegate makes any code that uses the MOC will be dependent on the app delegate and why that’s not a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate-part-2/#more-243&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about why putting the MOC in the app delegate is a violation of the Single Responsibility Principle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about why putting the MOC in your app delegate makes you dependent on Core Data for your application’s persistence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift Robot Arm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/swift-robot-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 22:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/swift-robot-arm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a previous &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/elixir-robots/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote about controlling my OWI robot arm with Elixir. Well, I decided to port that to Swift!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In that &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/elixir-robots/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, there’s a link to some code that does it in Objective-C with IOKit. I first tried to just do a straight port and use IOKit in Swift. That didn’t work to well. The IOKit API is an old Core Foundation library and even has some old &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Component_Object_Model&#34;&gt;COM&lt;/a&gt; style APIs. There’s some complex macros as well that do not even get transferred to Swift, so you have to find their definition and and put them in a Swift constant or function. I couldn’t even get it to compile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
