<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Numerology on Rod Schmidt</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/tags/numerology/</link><description>Recent content in Numerology on Rod Schmidt</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:26:12 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rodschmidt.com/tags/numerology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Numerology: 17 Years in the App Store (Part 4)</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:26:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-4/</guid><description>This is part 4 of my blog series on the history of my app Numerology. See Part 3 here.
The First App Store Version In 2008, Apple announced the App Store and I applied for an Apple Developer membership ($99/year), so I could sell apps on the App Store. Everyone else did the same and Apple was swamped. Despite applying as soon as possible, I didn’t get approved for about 6 months.</description></item><item><title>Numerology: 17 Years in the App Store (Part 3)</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 10:27:03 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-3/</guid><description>This is part 3 of my blog series on the history of my app Numerology. See Part 2 here.
The Birth of Cocoa In 2001, Apple released the first version of Mac OS X 10.0, the first desktop version of their new OS based on NEXTStep. All the great APIs from NeXTStep (hence the NS prefixes to all the class names and such) together were called Cocoa.
Now I finally had my chance to use the wonderful platform I’d been wanting to use for almost a decade.</description></item><item><title>Numerology: 17 Years in the App Store (Part 2)</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:59:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-2/</guid><description>This is part 2 of my blog series on the history of my app Numerology. See Part 1 here.
The First Version It was the very early 90’s. Steve Jobs was at NeXT. I had some model of Macintosh II running on a 680x0 processor. I also had a compiler for C with object-oriented extensions (basically a subset of C++), called THINK C, with a class library called TCL, or the Think Class Library.</description></item><item><title>Numerology: 17 Years in the App Store (Part 1)</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:31:32 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-1/</guid><description>Introduction My app, Numerology, has been in the Apple app store for over 17 years. During that time, it and its variations (lite version, Mac version) have been downloaded over 188,000 times, and made almost $150,000 in profit.
Numerology Icon
It’s ran on just about every Apple iPhone, iPad, and Mac. Before the App Store, it even ran on classic macOS machines.
It’s been through technology changes such as moving from Think C to Objective-C to Swift; the Think Class Library to UIKit to SwiftUI; classic to modern macOS, 68K chips to PowerPC chips to Intel chips and then to Apple Silicon.</description></item></channel></rss>