<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lisp on Rod Schmidt</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/tags/lisp/</link><description>Recent content in Lisp on Rod Schmidt</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:10:57 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rodschmidt.com/tags/lisp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mixing Swift and Clojure in Your iOS App - Scittle</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/scittle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:10:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/scittle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/s7-scheme/"&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt;, I showed how to embed a S7 Scheme interpreter in an iOS app. This time, I will show you how to embed a &lt;a href="https://clojurescript.org"&gt;ClojureScript&lt;/a&gt; interpreter, or at least a dialect of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://clojure.org"&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; itself, runs on the JVM, and there’s not really a way to embed the JVM in an iOS app. Maybe once &lt;a href="https://github.com/swiftlang/swift-java"&gt;swift-java&lt;/a&gt; gets rolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is &lt;a href="https://www.graalvm.org/"&gt;GraalVM&lt;/a&gt;, which lets you compile java code to native code, but it doesn’t support compiling for iOS. &lt;a href="https://babashka.org"&gt;Babashka&lt;/a&gt;, which is a native Clojure dialect interpreter uses GraalVM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mixing Swift and Lisp in Your iOS App - S7 Scheme</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/s7-scheme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 21:07:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/s7-scheme/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I am a fan of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lisp_%28programming_language%29"&gt;Lisp&lt;/a&gt;. I was first attracted to it because it was the original language of artificial intelligence because of its ability to manipulate symbols and its own code. I spent a whole year using Lisp in a series of courses on artificial intelligence in college. I became quite adept at using it and quite enjoyed using it as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="my-obsession"&gt;My Obsession&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve become kind of obsessed with being able to use Lisp in my iOS apps. I want to put a Lisp interpreter in my app and program my business logic in Lisp. Every once in an awhile I get the urge to figure it out, try, and fail. This keeps happening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>