<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Clean Architecture on Rod Schmidt</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/tags/clean-architecture/</link><description>Recent content in Clean Architecture on Rod Schmidt</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 17:47:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rodschmidt.com/tags/clean-architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Swift UI &amp; App Architecture: A New Approach Required</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/swift-ui-app-architecture-a-new-approach-required/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 17:47:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/swift-ui-app-architecture-a-new-approach-required/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With SwiftUI, everything has changed. As Brent Simmons said, it’s the end of the NeXT era and the beginning of the Swift era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the coming of SwiftUI, most of our app architectures are no longer valid (or at least parts of them). They need to be adjusted. MVC is certainly out. In fact, even controllers seem to be out. From Apple’s content, it seems all we have is models and views, and that’s true. Bindings have seemingly replaced controllers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Two More Examples of Clean Architecture</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/two-more-examples-of-clean-architecture/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 18:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/two-more-examples-of-clean-architecture/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently found two more examples of Clean Architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one is called CosyHome and is an example iOS application for a home heating system developed using &lt;a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uncle-bob/2012/08/13/the-clean-architecture.html"&gt;Clean Architecture&lt;/a&gt; and developed with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Acceptance_test%E2%80%93driven_development"&gt;Acceptance Test Driven Development&lt;/a&gt; (ATDD) using &lt;a href="http://fitnesse.org"&gt;Fitnesse&lt;/a&gt;. Fitnesse is something I&amp;rsquo;d like to dive more into and could be a future post. Let me know if you&amp;rsquo;re interested. You can find CosyHome &lt;a href="https://github.com/paulstringer/CosyHome"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other example is CleanNote that applies Clean Architecture to an iOS and Mac application. You can find that one &lt;a href="https://github.com/dcutting/CleanNote"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Clean Architecture: An Example</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/the-clean-architecture-an-example/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 21:33:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/the-clean-architecture-an-example/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I’d like to take an example iOS app written with an MVC architecture and show you what the example would be with a Clean Swift architecture. The example I’ve chosen to use is the Quiz app from chapter 1 of the 3rd edition of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/iOS-Programming-Ranch-Guide-Guides/dp/0321821521/ref=sr_1_7?crid=393OBE770KCSR&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=big+nerd+ranch+ios+programming&amp;amp;qid=1586836438&amp;amp;sprefix=Big+nerd+ranch%2Caps%2C182&amp;amp;sr=8-7"&gt;iOS Programming: The Big Nerd Ranch Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Quiz is a simple app that is like flash cards. It looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;img style="display: block; margin: 0.7rem auto; border: 1px solid black; margin-bottom: 0px;" 
 src="https://rodschmidt.com/images/quiz.png" 
 title="" 
 alt=""
 
 &gt;
 &lt;p style="text-align: center; font-size: smaller;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Clean Architecture: An Introduction</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/the-clean-architecture-an-introduction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:33:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/the-clean-architecture-an-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the last &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/moving-towards-the-clean-architecture-for-apple-development/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about various architectures used as alternatives to MVC, in a attempt to solve MVCs problems, such as Massive View Controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I would like to introduce you to another architecture, which seems to me to be the best starting point for your app’s architecture: the Clean Architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I first ran into the Clean Architecture in one of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WpkDN78P884"&gt;Uncle Bob’s presentations on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. At first, I kind of wrote it off as a typical Java over-engineered design pattern. It wasn’t until earlier this year, probably years later after my initial discovery, that I ran into it again. I was looking for a better app architecture after an experience working for a large company with a large iOS team (with about 11 developers) and all the issues they had getting the app to work and test it. I kind of became obsessed with figuring out how to make an app easier to test. I searched the internet for app architectures and studied them. It took me awhile to get my head around the Clean Architecture, but once I did, I decided it would be my starting point for an app architecture.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>