<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on Rod Schmidt</title>
    <link>/tags/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on Rod Schmidt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:09:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>App: The Human Story - My Prize</title>
      <link>/posts/app-the-human-story-my-prize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/app-the-human-story-my-prize/</guid>
      <description>A while back I wrote a blog post and entered it in a contest for App: The Human Story. I came in second, and for that I was awarded a custom app token from Matic. It finally came last week and here it is:
Now, I finally have a sign for my office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>App: The Human Story - My Story</title>
      <link>/posts/app-the-human-story-my-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 22:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/app-the-human-story-my-story/</guid>
      <description>There is a Kickstarter project that was started recently for a film titled App: The Human Story. It &amp;ldquo;is the story of the cultural phenomenon that touches all our lives.&amp;rdquo; It is about the people who make apps. Many of them are people I follow on blogs, and listen to on podcasts, and look up to. I simply had to back the project, and I did. The producers of the film, on their blog, have asked that others involved in apps write about their own stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Start</title>
      <link>/posts/a-new-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 22:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-new-start/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed, my weblog has a new design and new content. I have switched from WordPress to Octopress and have used a new theme. So far, I like it. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to use Markdown instead of some slow web tool to write my posts.
My old blog was mostly political commentary and I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to remove that. Some of my most popular posts were the posts about my sabbatical that I took in the summer of 2002.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>