<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sabbatical on Rod Schmidt</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/sabbatical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sabbatical on Rod Schmidt</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2002 22:37:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/sabbatical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Sabbatical is Over</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-sabbatical-is-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2002 22:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-sabbatical-is-over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is officially the last day of my sabbatical. Friday was my birthday and Monday is the day to begin anew. I had hoped that my sabbatical would bring spectacular changes to my world, but it did not. However I still think it was a good thing. It gave me a lot of time to reflect on what I want to do with my life and it helped me come to peace with how things are. I believe I&amp;rsquo;ve grown spiritually and am more at peace with myself. I am increasingly interested in Zen Buddhism, which seems to suit me particularly well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texas Tour - Lubbock Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/texas-tour-lubbock-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2002 22:33:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/texas-tour-lubbock-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, August 14th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wednesday morning I got back in the Jeep and started my trip home. My plan was to stay the night in Lubbock, then Albuquerque for a day with my folks and then back home. I got to Lubbock in the afternoon, but Patricia and Robert weren&amp;rsquo;t there. Instead, I was greeted by their 16 year old daughter, Christine. On my previous visit, Christine had been in Vietnam, where she had been for the last 6 weeks. Her parents had told me a lot about her as most parents do. Patricia had described her as &amp;ldquo;16 going on 25&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texas Tour - JFK</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/texas-tour-jfk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2002 22:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/texas-tour-jfk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, August 11th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning, I decided to go downtown and check out the JFK museum. John F. Kennedy was assasinated in Dallas on November 3rd, 1963. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t alive then, but I can imagine and I believe that it was a day that affected America even more than September 11th. Here was a president that many people admired and looked up to. Shortly after he was assasinated the decade of the 60&amp;rsquo;s went into full swing and changed America forever. Vietnam, the assasination of Robert Kennedy and Martin Luther King, race riots, the drug culture. All these things occurred and much more. America was never the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texas Tour - Arlington</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/texas-tour-arlington/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2002 22:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/texas-tour-arlington/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, August 13th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I met my friend Marc at his house and we headed off to the game. This game is kind of a milestone in my quest to visit every major league ball park. It will be my 20th team. Just ten more to go (barring expansion or contraction).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;span style=&#34;float: right; padding-left: 10px; &#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img style=&#34;border: 1px solid black;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/The_Ballpark_at_Arlington.jpg&#34; title=&#34;The Ballpark at Arlington&#34; alt=&#34;The Ballpark at Arlington&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center; font-size: smaller&#34;&gt;The Ballpark at Arlington&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dallas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dallas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2002 22:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dallas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 8th - August 14th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thurday morning I drove up to Dallas. It took about 4 hours and I checked into another extended stay motel. Originally, I had planned to stay in Dallas for a week, just like in Austin, but my Austin experience changed my plans. I was going to leave on the 14th, after the baseball game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Again, the idea was the same. To just be there and experience Dallas. However, there were a few things I wanted to do. There&amp;rsquo;s an Apple Store in Plano, a town just north of Dallas. Apple has been opening stores all over the country, but none yet in Utah, so I had to go check it out. Also, I wanted to check out downtown and see some JFK stuff, and of course the Texas Rangers are in nearby Arlington.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Austin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/austin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2002 22:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/austin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 4th - August 8th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spent Sunday through Thursday morning in Austin. Austin was the main reason I came to Texas. I wanted to get a feel for it and see if I might want to live here. Austin has a lot of high technology companies and has a lot of culture and art. Basically a lot of creative people. Fortune has ranked it in the top 10 for the best cities for singles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texas Tour - San Antonio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/texas-tour-san-antonio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2002 22:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/texas-tour-san-antonio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday, August 5th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today was my first full day in Austin. I decided to take a drive down to San Antonio, which was just about an hour and half south. I wanted to see the Alamo, and my friend Laury had told me about the cool river walk there. So off I went.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;span style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 10px;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img style=&#34;border: 1px solid black;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/The_Alamo.jpg&#34; title=&#34;The Alamo&#34; alt=&#34;The Alamo&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center; font-size: smaller&#34;&gt;The Alamo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those of you who are not familiar with the Alamo (miss a little school, did we?), here&amp;rsquo;s the deal. The Alamo was a fort in Texas when Texas declared their independence from Mexico. Santa Ana brought his troops into Texas and the Alamo was the first line of defense for Texas. Texas was not ready to fight Santa Ana yet and the Alamo had to slow down Santa Ana enough so Texas could get ready. Some legendary figures were at the Alamo, including my boyhood favorite, Davy Crockett. Every last man who fought at the Alamo died there, but they slowed Santa Ana down enough and they inspired the rest of Texas, who cried &amp;ldquo;Remember the Alamo&amp;rdquo;! Eventually Texas won her independence from Mexico and became an independent nation and of course joined the United States not long after. Some say Texas never officially joined the U.S. and is still an independent nation, but it is not recognized as such.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texas Tour - Lubbock</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/texas-tour-lubbock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2002 21:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/texas-tour-lubbock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, August 3rd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From Albuquerque, I decided to go half way to Austin, and stay the night with a recent friend of the family and her family. I had just met her when I had been up to Montana this summer and she had offered to let me stay with her and her family when I went to Texas. In the directions she gave me to get to her house she mentioned that there was a steel house that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t miss. She was right. However, she didn&amp;rsquo;t mention that it was their house that her husband had been building for 27 years!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texas Tour - Albuquerque</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/texas-tour-albuquerque/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2002 21:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/texas-tour-albuquerque/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, July 30th - Friday, August 2nd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, I left for my trip to Texas. On the way though I stopped in Albuquerque. I was born there and my parents currently live there. I stayed until Saturday. I was a nice relaxing time and it was nice to see my parents. We went out to dinner one night at a New Orleans place and we saw K-19: The WidowMaker and Signs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never Say Never (Again)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-say-never-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2002 04:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-say-never-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 1st, 2002 - Gardiner, Montana&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week I went up to Montana with my parents. Today, my mom and I decided to take a raft trip down the river that flows through Gardiner and down Yankee Jim Canyon. We&amp;rsquo;ve been on rafting trips before. Nothing tricky, just nice gentle trips with a few small rapids. We asked around and were pointed towards an outfit about a mile down the road. A place called Big Sky Whitewater.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steve Garvey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/steve-garvey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2002 04:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/steve-garvey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always like to see the Dodger&amp;rsquo;a AAA team when they come to Salt Lake. Last year, that team, moved from Albuquerque to Las Vegas and became the Las Vegas 51&amp;rsquo;s (51 being a reference to Area 51). After my trip I checked the Salt Lake Stingers&amp;rsquo; schedule and saw that the 51&amp;rsquo;s were in town. I further noticed that Thursday night was Steve Garvey night!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Steve Garvey was my favorite player when I was a kid. At first it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem like much of a big deal. I thought I go down and get his autograph and it would be no big thing. But, as the game got closer I got a little more excited. I went to Gart&amp;rsquo;s Sporting Goods and bought an official major league baseball in a little display case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Coast Tour - Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2002 04:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, June 18, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trip home was uneventful. Got back about 2 pm. Once back, I felt strangely alone and isolated. On the road, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t felt like this at all, despite the fact that I had been alone most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But, it also nice to be back in my nice house, with my own bed. Later that night I played softball on DSW&amp;rsquo;s team. DSW (Dahlin, Smith, and White), was the company I worked before I took my sabbatical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Coast Tour - Mission Viejo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-mission-viejo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2002 04:43:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-mission-viejo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday, June 17th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I left early, about 8am. I wanted to get an early start so I could check out Mission Viejo and then make a good start on my way home. I lived in Mission Viejo for about 10 years. I went to grade school and junior high school there. I really loved the California life style there. The athletic programs were excellent and I was a well known baseball and soccer player in the community. Made the all-star little league team and was drafted early into the senior major league, skipping the senior minors. When we left I was about to enter high school and had just made a travelling soccer club.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Coast Tour - San Diego</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-san-diego/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2002 04:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-san-diego/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, June 16th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the morning, Ron and Roe took me out to breakfast in downtown LA at a cozy little old restaurant surrounded by skyscrapers. It was good standard fare. After we got back I packed up and headed south to San Diego.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About halfway between LA and San Diego is a town called Mission Viejo. I had lived there for 10 years before I moved to Utah. My plan was to stop there and revisit my childhood. I did exit off the freeway, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything and I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have the time. The Padres game started at 2pm. So I got back on the freeway. I would come back to Mission Viejo later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Coast Tour - Los Angeles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-los-angeles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2002 03:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-los-angeles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, June 15th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After spending the night in Palo Alto, I started down the freeway to LA the next morning. Nothing really to write about here. Just your standard freeway drive. However, the traffic was horrible. Seemed like every half-hour or so you ran into stop and go traffic. Not fun. Just this alone made me think I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to live here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My friend, Laury&amp;rsquo;s sister and brother-in-law live in LA. Laury let them know I was coming so I called them and got directions to their place. Arrived about 5pm. Ron and Roe were very nice and gracious to let me stay in their place. I convinced Ron to come to game with me (Yea, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to drive) and we headed off to the Dodger game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zen and the Art of Nothing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/zen-and-the-art-of-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2002 03:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/zen-and-the-art-of-nothing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried everything when it comes to trying to meet women. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried dating services, personal ads, phone ads, internet dating, blind dates, being set up by friends, going to bars, and even asking out complete strangers. The most I&amp;rsquo;ve ended up with is a relationship that lasts for 6 months, but feels more like 2. I&amp;rsquo;ve told myself that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried everything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about this today when suddenly I had a Zen moment. I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting a lot of these ever since I really started thinking about my sabbatical and what I want to do. I find these paradoxical and oxymoronic thoughts absolutely delightful. On the surface they seem absurd, but then a light bulb goes off and you somehow understand. But if you try to analyze why its true then your mind gets lost running in circles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Coast Tour - San Francisco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2002 02:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-san-francisco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday, June 14th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;span style=&#34;float: right; padding-left: 10px; &#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img style=&#34;border: 1px solid black;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Evergreen_Road.jpg&#34; title=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center; font-size: smaller&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today started off with a great drive through more evergreen lined roads. That lasted till about midday. Then the road turned into a more freeway like drive with the golden hills of central California as the view, Eventually, I passed through the Golden Gate Bridge (horrible traffic) and settled in Palo Alto.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 10px;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img style=&#34;border: 1px solid black;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Miata.jpg&#34; title=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center; font-size: smaller&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Coast Tour - Oregon Coast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-oregon-coast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2002 02:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-oregon-coast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, June 13th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;span style=&#34;float: right; padding-left: 10px; &#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img style=&#34;border: 1px solid black;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/OregonCoast2-300x225.jpg&#34; title=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center; font-size: smaller&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today started off well. Found my way to the PCH, flipped the top down, and right away I was on a single lane road with no one in front of or behind me. That didn&amp;rsquo;t last long however. Kept going through towns where you have to slow down for the traffic. But every so often you hit a stretch of road and its just you and the road. You, and the road, surrounded by a bunch of tall evergreen trees providing shade. Perfect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Coast Tour - Seattle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2002 00:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-seattle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, June 12th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Took my time getting started and probably left Portland around 10am. Dez lent me some audio books (Thanks Dez) and I leisurely drove to Seattle arriving at about 3pm. Had the top down most of the way, but had to put it up about an hour outside of Seattle because I was starting to get sunburned. Its 90 degrees in Seattle today!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img style=&#34;display: block; margin: 0.7rem auto; border: 1px solid black; margin-bottom: 0px;&#34; &#xA;       src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Safeco_Field-300x225.jpg&#34; &#xA;       title=&#34;Safeco Field&#34; &#xA;       alt=&#34;Safeco Field&#34;&#xA;       &#xA;  &gt;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center; font-size: smaller;&#34;&gt;Safeco Field&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Coast Tour - Portland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-portland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2002 23:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/west-coast-tour-portland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, June 11th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The whole purpose of the west coast tour is too see the west coast baseball teams I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen yet (Seattle and San Diego) and to drive my Miata down the coast. So to that end I got up early and left at 5am and drove 12 hours with a few stops for lunch and rest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img style=&#34;display: block; margin: 0.7rem auto; border: 1px solid black; margin-bottom: 0px;&#34; &#xA;       src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/the_way_to_Portland-300x225.jpg&#34; &#xA;       title=&#34;On the way to Portland&#34; &#xA;       alt=&#34;On the way to Portland&#34;&#xA;       &#xA;  &gt;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center; font-size: smaller;&#34;&gt;On the way to Portland&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlanta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/atlanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2002 20:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/atlanta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, June 7th, 2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday I caught a flight to Atlanta&#xA;(thanks to my sister&amp;rsquo;s buddy pass) and arrived at about 2:30 PM EST. Caught&#xA;the MARTA (Atlanta equivalent of TRAX) right from the airport to downtown.&#xA;My hotel was only a couple of blocks from my stop. One thing I notice is the&#xA;humidity. To me, it actually felt good. Keeps your skin moist and when it&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;hot you actually sweat. Just the way it should be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
