<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apple Platforms on Rod Schmidt</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/tags/apple-platforms/</link><description>Recent content in Apple Platforms on Rod Schmidt</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 21:07:11 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rodschmidt.com/tags/apple-platforms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mixing Swift and Lisp in Your iOS App - S7 Scheme</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/s7-scheme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 21:07:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/s7-scheme/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I am a fan of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lisp_%28programming_language%29"&gt;Lisp&lt;/a&gt;. I was first attracted to it because it was the original language of artificial intelligence because of its ability to manipulate symbols and its own code. I spent a whole year using Lisp in a series of courses on artificial intelligence in college. I became quite adept at using it and quite enjoyed using it as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="my-obsession"&gt;My Obsession&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve become kind of obsessed with being able to use Lisp in my iOS apps. I want to put a Lisp interpreter in my app and program my business logic in Lisp. Every once in an awhile I get the urge to figure it out, try, and fail. This keeps happening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Numerology: 17 Years in the App Store (Part 6)</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:43:03 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-6/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 6 of my blog series on the history of my app Numerology. See Part 5 &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-5"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we left off, Numerology was chugging along, slowly making less and less each month. First $300, then $200, sometimes as low as $100. Sometimes it would spurt back up to $300.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This continued until fairly recently. In 2024, I noticed a competitor that always showed up first in the App Store search results when you searched for ‘numerology’. I decided to look into them a little more. According to Sensor Tower, their app was making over $5,000/month on the Apple App Store. They had an Android app as well, and it was making $5,000/month as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Numerology: 17 Years in the App Store (Part 5)</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:30:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 5 of my blog series on the history of my app Numerology. See Part 4 &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-4"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was probably the first numerology app on the App Store. If you searched for numerology, my app would be first in the results. At some point this was no longer true. A competitor came out and my sales started to go down. Today, in 2025, there are possibly over a 100 numerology apps on the store.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Numerology: 17 Years in the App Store (Part 4)</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:26:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 4 of my blog series on the history of my app Numerology. See Part 3 &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-3"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-first-app-store-version"&gt;The First App Store Version&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2008, Apple announced the App Store and I applied for an Apple Developer membership ($99/year), so I could sell apps on the App Store. Everyone else did the same and Apple was swamped. Despite applying as soon as possible, I didn’t get approved for about 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Numerology: 17 Years in the App Store (Part 3)</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 10:27:03 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 3 of my blog series on the history of my app Numerology. See Part 2 &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-2"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-birth-of-cocoa"&gt;The Birth of Cocoa&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2001, Apple released the first version of Mac OS X 10.0, the first desktop version of their new OS based on NEXTStep. All the great APIs from NeXTStep (hence the NS prefixes to all the class names and such) together were called Cocoa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I finally had my chance to use the wonderful platform I’d been wanting to use for almost a decade. My full-time job was still with Java and enterprise world and it was increasingly not fun. I spent my off-time learning Cocoa. My first app was not Numerology though. It was an app called PhoneWord that found all the words you could make from a phone number. For example, from the phone number 555-5299 you could get 555-JAZZ.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Numerology: 17 Years in the App Store (Part 2)</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:59:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 2 of my blog series on the history of my app Numerology. See Part 1 &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-first-version"&gt;The First Version&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the very early 90’s. Steve Jobs was at NeXT. I had some model of Macintosh II running on a 680x0 processor. I also had a compiler for C with object-oriented extensions (basically a subset of C++), called &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/THINK_C"&gt;THINK C&lt;/a&gt;, with a class library called TCL, or the Think Class Library. For more about THINK C, see this &lt;a href="http://preserve.mactech.com/articles/mactech/Vol.05/05.10/ThinkCTutor/index.html"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Numerology: 17 Years in the App Store (Part 1)</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:31:32 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My app, &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id292749698"&gt;Numerology&lt;/a&gt;, has been in the Apple app store for over 17 years. During that time, it and its variations (lite version, Mac version) have been downloaded over 188,000 times, and made almost $150,000 in profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;img style="display: block; margin: 0.7rem auto; border: 1px solid black; margin-bottom: 0px;" 
 src="https://rodschmidt.com/images/numerology-logo.png" 
 title="Numerology Icon" 
 alt="Numerology Icon"
 
 width="128"
 
 &gt;
 &lt;p style="text-align: center; font-size: smaller;"&gt;Numerology Icon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It’s ran on just about every Apple iPhone, iPad, and Mac. Before the App Store, it even ran on classic macOS machines.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pointfree's SyncUps App: A Great Example Architecture for a SwiftUI App</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/syncups/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 10:41:54 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/syncups/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In comments to my last article on &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/composable-architecture-experience"&gt;The Composable Architecture&lt;/a&gt; readers have asked about examples of how I think an app should be written. In the article, I did mention my previous posts, which have examples for Clean Swift and MVVM, but those were written for UIKit. SwiftUI didn’t exist at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this article will talk about what I think is a great example of architecture for a SwiftUI app. Pointfree’s own &lt;a href="https://github.com/pointfreeco/syncups"&gt;SyncUps&lt;/a&gt; app. The example actually has 2 apps, one showing tree-based navigation, and one showing stack-based navigation. For this article, I will just focus on the stack-based example.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Composable Architecture: My 3 Year Experience</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/composable-architecture-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 11:35:37 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/composable-architecture-experience/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently finished a 3 year stint with a company that uses the Composable Architecture (&lt;a href="https://github.com/pointfreeco/swift-composable-architecture"&gt;TCA&lt;/a&gt;)
from &lt;a href="https://pointfree.co"&gt;PointFree&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to write about my experiences with TCA and some of
the problems I see with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Brandon Williams and Stephen Cellis, the creators of TCA, are absolutely brilliant, and what
they have managed to pull off with the creation of TCA is amazing. However, It’s just the two of them,
and nobody, or no thing, is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Swift UI &amp; App Architecture: A New Approach Required</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/swift-ui-app-architecture-a-new-approach-required/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 17:47:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/swift-ui-app-architecture-a-new-approach-required/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With SwiftUI, everything has changed. As Brent Simmons said, it’s the end of the NeXT era and the beginning of the Swift era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the coming of SwiftUI, most of our app architectures are no longer valid (or at least parts of them). They need to be adjusted. MVC is certainly out. In fact, even controllers seem to be out. From Apple’s content, it seems all we have is models and views, and that’s true. Bindings have seemingly replaced controllers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Clean Architecture: An Example</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/the-clean-architecture-an-example/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 21:33:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/the-clean-architecture-an-example/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I’d like to take an example iOS app written with an MVC architecture and show you what the example would be with a Clean Swift architecture. The example I’ve chosen to use is the Quiz app from chapter 1 of the 3rd edition of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/iOS-Programming-Ranch-Guide-Guides/dp/0321821521/ref=sr_1_7?crid=393OBE770KCSR&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=big+nerd+ranch+ios+programming&amp;amp;qid=1586836438&amp;amp;sprefix=Big+nerd+ranch%2Caps%2C182&amp;amp;sr=8-7"&gt;iOS Programming: The Big Nerd Ranch Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Quiz is a simple app that is like flash cards. It looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;img style="display: block; margin: 0.7rem auto; border: 1px solid black; margin-bottom: 0px;" 
 src="https://rodschmidt.com/images/quiz.png" 
 title="" 
 alt=""
 
 &gt;
 &lt;p style="text-align: center; font-size: smaller;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Model View Controller: Problems and Solutions</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/model-view-controller-problems-and-solutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 21:41:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/model-view-controller-problems-and-solutions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Model View Controller&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;MVC&lt;/em&gt; is the application architecture used by default for applications on all Apple platforms. Most of the tools, frameworks, and docs from Apple all talk about it and support it. In MVC, objects are assigned 1 of 3 roles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model&lt;/strong&gt; - objects that encapsulate and manage the data the application works with (this includes persistence). The data typically represents things in the real world like an employee, hardware part, or a picture that is being drawn. More abstract things can also be part of a model such as a hiring process. When data in the model changes it notifies a controller object, typically via delegation or notifications. Model objects should have no knowledge of the user interface and be reusable in other applications in similar problem domains or on other devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Part 4: What Are the Downsides to Putting the Core Data MOC in the App Delegate</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/part-4-what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 21:49:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/part-4-what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/part-3-what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/"&gt;part 3&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about why putting the MOC in the app delegate makes any code that uses the MOC will be dependent on the app delegate and why that’s not a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate-part-2/#more-243"&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about why putting the MOC in the app delegate is a violation of the Single Responsibility Principle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/"&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about why putting the MOC in your app delegate makes you dependent on Core Data for your application’s persistence.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Part 3: What Are The Downsides to Putting the Core Data MOC in the App Delegate</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/part-3-what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 21:28:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/part-3-what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate-part-2/#more-243"&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about why putting the MOC in the app delegate is a violation of the Single Responsibility Principle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/"&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about why putting the MOC in your app delegate makes you dependent on Core Data for your application’s persistence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I like to talk about the 3rd reason I gave in part 1, which is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any code you write that uses &lt;code&gt;myManagedObjectContext&lt;/code&gt; will be dependent on the App Delegate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any code you write in another source file, say a subclass of &lt;code&gt;UITableViewController&lt;/code&gt; for example, that uses &lt;code&gt;myManagedObjectContext&lt;/code&gt; from the app delegate will be dependent on the app delegate. In Objective-C this would mean you would need a &lt;code&gt;#import &amp;quot;AppDelegate.h&lt;/code&gt; statement in your subclass’ source file. Every source file that accesses the app delegate’s MOC would need that import, which would bring in everything else the app delegate uses. In Swift, you don’t need the import statement, but it would increase your compile times, as it would in Objective-C as well. Every time you made a change to the app delegate, any source files that accessed the MOC in the app delegate would have to be recompiled.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Part 2: What Are The Downsides to Putting the Core Data MOC in the App Delegate</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 22:33:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In my previous &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, I gave some reasons why putting the Core Data MOC in your app delegate was a bad idea. Those reasons were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app delegate is managing the Core Data stack. Classes should only have one responsibility. The app delegate is already responsible for managing application lifecycle. It shouldn’t be managing the Core Data stack as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are completely dependent on Core Data and using it as your persistence method for your app. What if you decide to switch to Realm or something?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any code you write that uses &lt;code&gt;myManagedObjectContext&lt;/code&gt; will be dependent on the App Delegate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any tests you write will be dependent on the App Delegate and Core Data and will be hard to test and slow as a result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous &lt;a href="https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, we talked about how putting the Core Data MOC in your app delegate makes your app dependent on Core Data as your persistence mechanism and makes it hard to use something else. In this post, I’d like to talk about &lt;strong&gt;reason #1: That your app delegate is already responsible for managing the application life cycle and it shouldn’t be responsible for the Core Data stack as well&lt;/strong&gt;. This comes from the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SOLID_(object-oriented_design)"&gt;SOLID&lt;/a&gt; principles of good object-oriented design, specifically the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single_responsibility_principle"&gt;Single Responsibility Principle&lt;/a&gt;, which states:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>3 Ways To Fix Your iOS Testing Woes</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/3-ways-to-fix-your-ios-testing-woes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 16:55:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/3-ways-to-fix-your-ios-testing-woes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of companies have constant problems testing their iOS apps. Here are some ways to fix or ease them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="1-dont-make-developers-run-or-write-ui-tests"&gt;1. Don’t Make Developers Run or Write UI Tests&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UI tests are black box tests and test the app from the perspective of the user. Your developers are the worst choice to test the app from this viewpoint and you need a fresh set of eyes for those tests. The QA engineer’s job is to test the app from the user’s viewpoint. Your QA Engineers should write these tests. Plus, UI tests run entirely too slow for your developers to run them all the time and are much too failure prone. Don’t waste their time by making them write and run these tests.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What are the Downsides to Putting the Core Data MOC in the App Delegate?</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 20:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I saw this question on the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/iOSProgramming"&gt;iOSProgramming&lt;/a&gt; topic in reddit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a number of different ways to access the NSManagedObjectContext when working with Core Data, but I was wondering if there are any downsides to the way I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing it. Basically, I stick a computed variable in the AppDelegate, and grab it when I need it&amp;hellip; Please let me know if you see any flaws&amp;hellip; If not, feel free to use it!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>