<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apple Platforms on Rod Schmidt</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/tags/apple-platforms/</link><description>Recent content in Apple Platforms on Rod Schmidt</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:59:09 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rodschmidt.com/tags/apple-platforms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Numerology: 17 Years in the App Store (Part 2)</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:59:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-2/</guid><description>This is part 2 of my blog series on the history of my app Numerology. See Part 1 here.
The First Version It was the very early 90’s. Steve Jobs was at NeXT. I had some model of Macintosh II running on a 680x0 processor. I also had a compiler for C with object-oriented extensions (basically a subset of C++), called THINK C, with a class library called TCL, or the Think Class Library.</description></item><item><title>Numerology: 17 Years in the App Store (Part 1)</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:31:32 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/numerology-history-1/</guid><description>Introduction My app, Numerology, has been in the Apple app store for over 17 years. During that time, it and its variations (lite version, Mac version) have been downloaded over 188,000 times, and made almost $150,000 in profit.
Numerology Icon
It’s ran on just about every Apple iPhone, iPad, and Mac. Before the App Store, it even ran on classic macOS machines.
It’s been through technology changes such as moving from Think C to Objective-C to Swift; the Think Class Library to UIKit to SwiftUI; classic to modern macOS, 68K chips to PowerPC chips to Intel chips and then to Apple Silicon.</description></item><item><title>Pointfree's SyncUps App: A Great Example Architecture for a SwiftUI App</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/syncups/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 10:41:54 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/syncups/</guid><description>In comments to my last article on The Composable Architecture readers have asked about examples of how I think an app should be written. In the article, I did mention my previous posts, which have examples for Clean Swift and MVVM, but those were written for UIKit. SwiftUI didn’t exist at the time.
So, this article will talk about what I think is a great example of architecture for a SwiftUI app.</description></item><item><title>The Composable Architecture: My 3 Year Experience</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/composable-architecture-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 11:35:37 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/composable-architecture-experience/</guid><description>Introduction I recently finished a 3 year stint with a company that uses the Composable Architecture (TCA) from PointFree. I wanted to write about my experiences with TCA and some of the problems I see with it.
I think Brandon Williams and Stephen Cellis, the creators of TCA, are absolutely brilliant, and what they have managed to pull off with the creation of TCA is amazing. However, It’s just the two of them, and nobody, or no thing, is perfect.</description></item><item><title>Swift UI &amp; App Architecture: A New Approach Required</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/swift-ui-app-architecture-a-new-approach-required/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 17:47:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/swift-ui-app-architecture-a-new-approach-required/</guid><description>With SwiftUI, everything has changed. As Brent Simmons said, it’s the end of the NeXT era and the beginning of the Swift era.
With the coming of SwiftUI, most of our app architectures are no longer valid (or at least parts of them). They need to be adjusted. MVC is certainly out. In fact, even controllers seem to be out. From Apple’s content, it seems all we have is models and views, and that’s true.</description></item><item><title>The Clean Architecture: An Example</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/the-clean-architecture-an-example/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 21:33:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/the-clean-architecture-an-example/</guid><description>Today, I’d like to take an example iOS app written with an MVC architecture and show you what the example would be with a Clean Swift architecture. The example I’ve chosen to use is the Quiz app from chapter 1 of the 3rd edition of iOS Programming: The Big Nerd Ranch Guide.
The Quiz is a simple app that is like flash cards. It looks like this:
The Show Answer button will reveal the answer to the question and tapping on the Next Question button will display the next question.</description></item><item><title>Model View Controller: Problems and Solutions</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/model-view-controller-problems-and-solutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 21:41:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/model-view-controller-problems-and-solutions/</guid><description>Model View Controller or MVC is the application architecture used by default for applications on all Apple platforms. Most of the tools, frameworks, and docs from Apple all talk about it and support it. In MVC, objects are assigned 1 of 3 roles:
Model - objects that encapsulate and manage the data the application works with (this includes persistence). The data typically represents things in the real world like an employee, hardware part, or a picture that is being drawn.</description></item><item><title>Part 4: What Are the Downsides to Putting the Core Data MOC in the App Delegate</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/part-4-what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 21:49:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/part-4-what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</guid><description>In part 3, I talked about why putting the MOC in the app delegate makes any code that uses the MOC will be dependent on the app delegate and why that’s not a good thing.
In part 2, I talked about why putting the MOC in the app delegate is a violation of the Single Responsibility Principle.
In part 1, I talked about why putting the MOC in your app delegate makes you dependent on Core Data for your application’s persistence.</description></item><item><title>Part 3: What Are The Downsides to Putting the Core Data MOC in the App Delegate</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/part-3-what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 21:28:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/part-3-what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</guid><description>In part 2, I talked about why putting the MOC in the app delegate is a violation of the Single Responsibility Principle.
In part 1, I talked about why putting the MOC in your app delegate makes you dependent on Core Data for your application’s persistence.
Today I like to talk about the 3rd reason I gave in part 1, which is:
Any code you write that uses myManagedObjectContext will be dependent on the App Delegate.</description></item><item><title>Part 2: What Are The Downsides to Putting the Core Data MOC in the App Delegate</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 22:33:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate-part-2/</guid><description>In my previous post, I gave some reasons why putting the Core Data MOC in your app delegate was a bad idea. Those reasons were:
The app delegate is managing the Core Data stack. Classes should only have one responsibility. The app delegate is already responsible for managing application lifecycle. It shouldn’t be managing the Core Data stack as well. You are completely dependent on Core Data and using it as your persistence method for your app.</description></item><item><title>3 Ways To Fix Your iOS Testing Woes</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/3-ways-to-fix-your-ios-testing-woes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 16:55:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/3-ways-to-fix-your-ios-testing-woes/</guid><description>Lots of companies have constant problems testing their iOS apps. Here are some ways to fix or ease them.
1. Don’t Make Developers Run or Write UI Tests UI tests are black box tests and test the app from the perspective of the user. Your developers are the worst choice to test the app from this viewpoint and you need a fresh set of eyes for those tests. The QA engineer’s job is to test the app from the user’s viewpoint.</description></item><item><title>What are the Downsides to Putting the Core Data MOC in the App Delegate?</title><link>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 20:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rodschmidt.com/posts/what-are-the-downsides-to-putting-the-core-data-moc-in-the-app-delegate/</guid><description>I saw this question on the iOSProgramming topic in reddit:
I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a number of different ways to access the NSManagedObjectContext when working with Core Data, but I was wondering if there are any downsides to the way I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing it. Basically, I stick a computed variable in the AppDelegate, and grab it when I need it&amp;hellip; Please let me know if you see any flaws&amp;hellip; If not, feel free to use it!</description></item></channel></rss>